Guide to the William L. Taylor papers, 1954-2009 MS2287
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Publications, 1948-2009; Series 4; 15 Linear Feet
  - Race to the Top, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Report and Recommendations of the CCCR -- draft, undated; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Traiman, Susan, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Unpublished writing, undated; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Book with Marmur, undated; Series 4 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Report: Professional Opinions on School Guidance, William Bingham, Rutgers University, undated; Series 4 (Box 111, Folder 9)
- Photos, 1963-2004; Series 5; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Arranged by topic.
  Contains photographs of and by William L. Taylor. They date from 1963 to 2004.
  - Photos from March on Washington, 1963 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Photos for Passion of My Times, undated (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Swearing-in Ceremony at USCCR, 1965 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - William L. Taylor, undated (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - White House meeting, 1967; Series 5 (Map-folder 1)
- Audiovisual, 1975-2005; Series 6; 1 Linear Feet
  Arranged chronologically by date of recording.
  This series contains audiocassettes, videocassettes, and digital audio files of interviews, oral histories, and conferences featuring William L. Taylor. Many are from radio call-in programs such as the Diane Rehm Show, Talk of the Nation, the Larry King Show, the Kojo Nnamdi Show, and the Jim Bohannon Show. Topics of discussion include school desegregation, civil rights legislation, voting rights legislation, and Taylor's book, Passion of my Times. They date from 1975 to 2005.
  The links to these digital audio files can be accessed from computers on the GW campus. For assistance in accessing the digital files from an off campus computer, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.
  - Options in Education: "School Desegregation: Guess Who's Riding the Bus?", 1975 (Box 113, Cassette 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    A digital audio file exists. For assistance in accessing this digital file, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.
  - Larry King Show busing debate, 1981 October 20; Series 6; Original cassette label: LKS Busing debate 12-1 (Box 113, Cassette 2)
  - Larry King Show busing debate, 1981 October 20; Series 6; Original cassette label: LKS Busing debate 1-2 (Box 113, Cassette 3)
  - Voting Rights Act oral history with Ralph Neas [1 of 3], 1982; Series 6; Original cassette label: Taylor and Neas (Box 113, Cassette 4)
  - Voting Rights Act oral history with Ralph Neas [2 of 3], 1982; Series 6; Original cassette label: Neas and Taylor (Box 113, Cassette 5)
  - Voting Rights Act oral history with Ralph Neas [3 of 3], 1982; Series 6; Original cassette label: Neas and Taylor (Box 113, Cassette 6)
  - Civil rights interview, labeled Post-Grove City, 1984 October 5; Series 6; Original cassette label: Taylor/Post-Grove City 10-5-84 (Box 113, Cassette 7)
  - The Diane Rehm Show, 1986 February 2; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 8)
    This link to this digital audio file can be accessed from computers on the GW campus. For assistance in accessing this digital file from an off campus computer, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.
  - Alliance for Justice: Law Day Luncheon, William L. Taylor honoree, 1986 May 12; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 9)
  - The Diane Rehm Show, 1988 May 23; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 10)
  - The Diane Rehm Show, 1989 January 16; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 11)
  - Discussion of 1992 Bail Law Amendments, 1992 March 30; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 12)
  - Life and Times of Joe Rauh, 1992 November 17; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 13)
  - Jim Bohannon Show, 1993 August 24; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 14)
  - Southern Education Foundation Annual Conference: Abiding Civil Rights Issues, Part I, Taylor/Shaw, 1993 November 2; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 15)
  - WMAL: Brown v. Board of Education interview, William Taylor, 1994 May 15; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 16)
  - On the Line: Affirmative Action, Taylor debate with R. Cohen, 1995 February 10; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 17)
  - On the Line: Affirmative Action, Taylor debate with R. Cohen, 1995 February 10; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 18)
  - Derek McGinty Show, WAMU: Affirmative Action, 1995 February 13; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 19)
  - Jim Bohannon Show, 1995 January 16; Series 6; Original cassette label: jbs (Box 113, Cassette 20)
  - Crosstalk: Pam Coulter with Clint Bolick on Affirmative Action, Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 21)
  - Talk of the Nation: Affirmative Action, 1995 June 12; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 22)
  - On with Leon: William Taylor, 2005 May 7; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 23)
  - Kojo Nnamdi Show: Civil Rights after Rosa Parks, 2005 November 7; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 24)
  - Civil Rights oral history, undated; Series 6; Original cassette label: A: Cleveland/B: [illegible] interviews: Dixon (Box 113, Cassette 25)
  - WWLA July 21, NAACP, undated; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 26)
  - Civil Rights Commission Press Conference: Interview with Bill Taylor, Clarence Mitchell / Interview with James Roosevelt, Anthony Lewis, undated; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 27)
  - Bill Taylor: Paris Speech, 1988 October 8; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 28)
  - Sam Donaldson: Live in America, Bill Taylor, 2002 May 09; Series 6 (Box 113, Cassette 29)
  - The Passion of My Times C-SPAN videotape, undated; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 1)
  - Bill Taylor at the Ashcroft hearings, 2001 January 18; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 2)
  - William Taylor interviews; Dailies: Roger, Ralph, undated; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 3)
  - Prost case 20/20, 1995 May 12; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 4)
  - Bill Taylor interview, undated; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 5)
  - LCCR Awards dinner, 2001 May 09; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 6)
  - LCCR Humphrey Award, Bill Taylor intro video, 2001; Series 6 (Box 114, Videocassette 7)
  - All Things Considered. Profile: History and Role of the U.S. Civil Rights Commission, undated; Series 6 (Box 115, Cd 1)
  - 18 unlabeled microcassettes: Affirmative action interviews; and School Choice Forum April 1997, Series 6 (Box 115)